<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>battery &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/battery/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 06:16:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Too many stuffs in hand</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/03/04/too-many-stuffs-in-hand/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 06:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Several things that I need to do but failed (failed means didn&#8217;t finish or even not started yet), I tried my best during the weekend but the progress is not that pretty :(. I didn&#8217;t touch solr in the past week for the term vertor problem in distributed search, I&#8217;m going to try it out <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/03/04/too-many-stuffs-in-hand/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several things that I need to do but failed (failed means didn&#8217;t finish or even not started yet), I tried my best during the weekend but the progress is not that pretty :(.</p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t touch solr in the past week for the term vertor problem in distributed search, I&#8217;m going to try it out in the coming week but I have no confidence at all.</p>
<p>I do try to set up Windows Phone development environment but obvious I need more resource (read: memory) on either the Windows laptop or Windows VM on MBP, I even upgraded my Windows laptop (an HP) to Windows 7. However, it seems memory is still the problem. My next step is raising the memory for VM on MBP to 4G (later 6G, maybe) to see if it works better, but that will make WP7 development really a occasional hobby as I cannot leave it up and running for all the time. Pity MBP supports 8G memory only, I think under 16G I will have enough headroom for everything.</p>
<p>Playing with Android is still a fun, or maybe funny? hehe. I started working on that but Eclipse&#8217; or Android&#8217;s UI designer really sucks, I still need sometime to get used with it. I wish I can get this part done faster as this could be the only platform that I can try without cost.</p>
<p>Since the mail team was kind of slow releasing whatever we want, so I started digging into alternatives to see if I can speed up a little bit &#8211; I constantly update and build Android clients and also tried to build up some backend features with open source projects, this involved Postfix, atmail/roundcube, solr, and so on. This part didn&#8217;t go well either, mostly because I stuck in the front end features, and turned me back to backend stuffs again, but that means I&#8217;m not that helpful to the current project since front end features are much more important, at least at this stage.</p>
<p>Terminology extraction is much better than other projects, at least I finished a demo for JS extraction, it works wel for 95% cases, pity for those 5% leftovers, I cannot do anything about it since they have have either HTML mess up, or JS conflicts (well, maybe I can do something for later one, but not now since this is not a serious project so far).</p>
<p>What else? hmmm &#8230; seems almost all batteries @ home are having problems, from cell phone to lawn mower, from blower to iRobot. I did a lot research in the past couple of days on Lead Acid, Ni-Cd, Li-Ion, 12V, 18V, 24V, purchase, recycling, and so on, but good thing is that I&#8217;ve put all necessary orders and now just want for those batteries arriving.</p>
<p>Nothing else I think &#8230; the office will have network tuned in the coming week, probably I will have to run my own Wifi after that :-$</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
