<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>lighttpd &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/lighttpd/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 05:57:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>django, lighttpd, &#8230;</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/11/django-lighttpd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 05:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[django]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lighttpd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[python]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m trying to study Django more, this needs to get rid of the limitation of running test locally. I was doing port forwarding and then I thought, &#8220;anyway I will try deployment later on, why not just start the trial from now?&#8221; So, I started looking around, of course first thing came to mind is <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/11/django-lighttpd/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m trying to study Django more, this needs to get rid of the limitation of running test locally.</p>
<p>I was doing port forwarding and then I thought, &#8220;anyway I will try deployment later on, why not just start the trial from now?&#8221;</p>
<p>So, I started looking around, of course first thing came to mind is mod_python with apache httpd, but my Ubuntu has lighttpd running already (I have no idea when and why I deployed it), and then I thought, &#8220;yea, apache httpd is way too heavy, let me try lighttpd&#8221;.</p>
<p>It turned out lighttpd is not perfect in administration though it may get me some performance gain. I have to launch fastcgi by myself, and in a real production environment it means I need to write some monitoring (parent) process to make sure the fastcgi server is running for all the time.</p>
<p>Anyway I make django running on lighttpd, there are some URL mess and I still haven&#8217;t figured everything out, it seems django+lighttpd prefer application-per-domain instead of application-per-URI, I will check more to see if it is the case or not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
