<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>turbotax &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/turbotax/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 17:02:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>TurboTax and e-filing</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/03/23/turbotax-and-e-filing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 17:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[turbotax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had e-filing problem last year and even customer support people could not figure out what was the problem (BTW, it was the first time I saw people doing remote desktop thing for support which is pretty cool), so they end up with refunding my money paid for e-filing. I tried e-filing again this year <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/03/23/turbotax-and-e-filing/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had e-filing problem last year and even customer support people could not figure out what was the problem (BTW, it was the first time I saw people doing remote desktop thing for support which is pretty cool), so they end up with refunding my money paid for e-filing.</p>
<p>I tried e-filing again this year and same thing. Reading the help articles and discussions on the web doesn&#8217;t help too much. I tried to change SSL/certificate setting in IE, nothing helped, I&#8217;m on wired LAN so wireless problem should not be an issue to me, I tried on both Vista and XP but neither worked so &#8230;</p>
<p>I thought it could be because I&#8217;m using Chinese version of those Windows, so I installed everything on my corporate-issued laptop (thanks for the download version, easy to install anywhere you want), things are working like a charm.</p>
<p>I still need to dig out if it is network issue (such as TurboTax or IRS blocked Comcast which seems less possible), or it is actually Chinese edition problem &#8211; I would like to say the 2nd one is more reasonable.</p>
<p>However, I may only get the answer the coming year, since I&#8217;ve filed everything &#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
