<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>directtv &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/directtv/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 07:12:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>TV selection</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/01/07/tv-selection/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 07:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[directtv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was planning to get a bigger (52&#8243; LCD or even bigger) TV in the living room, and move current 26&#8243; CRT to bedroom, this can help me get rid of the bad habit of holding my laptop for all the time, especially before going to sleep. However, after reading recent news I think I <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/01/07/tv-selection/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was planning to get a bigger (52&#8243; LCD or even bigger) TV in the living room, and move current 26&#8243; CRT to bedroom, this can help me get rid of the bad habit of holding my laptop for all the time, especially before going to sleep.</p>
<p>However, after reading recent news I think I will hold the purchase for some time &#8211; news are talking about TV maker and cable providers could make 3D programs available for residential subscribers, which sounds really attractive.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve booked two set boxes from Direct TV, I don&#8217;t want to waste the converter so I did some cabling, and hook one of them up with the desktop. The quality is not that great as I can only use it as analog device, because Microsoft&#8217;s stupid design on Media Center (search &#8220;IR hardware not detected&#8221; you will know what it is), but good thing is that now I can watch netflix and TV in same room, and 22&#8243; LCD display is kind of acceptable.</p>
<p>I will wait for another month to make sure things won&#8217;t go crazy with new TV, and I may still go with an &#8220;old&#8221; regular TV if it doesn&#8217;t look too outdated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Switching to DirectTV</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/01/03/switching-to-directtv/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/01/03/switching-to-directtv/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 04:23:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[directtv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Comcast has a $69.99 promotion for Internet and cable bundle, but they refused to give me the price as I&#8217;m their subscriber already, so I ordered DirectTV and get things installed. Internet is way harder &#8211; AT&#38;T does not provide service in my area, and all other providers (satellite) are way too expensive. Luckily, while <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/01/03/switching-to-directtv/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Comcast has a $69.99 promotion for Internet and cable bundle, but they refused to give me the price as I&#8217;m their subscriber already, so I ordered DirectTV and get things installed.</p>
<p>Internet is way harder &#8211; AT&amp;T does not provide service in my area, and all other providers (satellite) are way too expensive. Luckily, while I chat online with Comcast representative for canceling my cable service, he gave me a $29.99 offer (vs. current ~$50), so I accepted the offer, and stopped looking around.</p>
<p>I have to look at this again after 6 months, I don&#8217;t think anything will be changed then, I may take a look at wireless provider (AT&amp;T or Verizon), at least make it a backup plan, so that I can cancel Comcast for some days and then subscribe again as a new customer.</p>
<p>Frankly speaking, I think maintaining TV subscription is a waste to me, since I seldom watch TV &#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/01/03/switching-to-directtv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
