<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>logmein &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/logmein/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 17:24:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>logmein is cool</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/08/14/logmein-is-cool/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 17:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logmein]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=616</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I was in Beijing I installed logmein on my mother&#8217;s desktop, and obviously this is a smart move. Yesterday she got some problem with her computer (missing the shortcut to the camera folder), usually, it would take me quite a while talking to her to know what&#8217;s happening there and then spend half an <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/08/14/logmein-is-cool/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was in Beijing I installed <a href="http://www.logmein.com/">logmein</a> on my mother&#8217;s desktop, and obviously this is a smart move.</p>
<p>Yesterday she got some problem with her computer (missing the shortcut to the camera folder), usually, it would take me quite a while talking to her to know what&#8217;s happening there and then spend half an hour or even more to get her understand what should be done to get things fixed.</p>
<p>Now, it becomes super easy &#8211; she knows how to enable logmein, and once she did that, I can get to her machine to check around and fix it right away (you know how easy it is, right?), and at the same time she can see what I have done to her machine so just in case she wants to learn some, she can ask questions and I can answer them right away.</p>
<p>This is a nice product, a great free service, I know big companies like Adobe, Microsoft, Cisco are all having similar products, just wish logmein can survive in the competition so that we can keep using it.</p>
<p>BTW, it supports Windows and Mac,both are running well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
