<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mobile phone &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/mobile-phone/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 05:58:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Saving my home network</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/12/28/saving-my-home-network/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 05:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linksys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wifi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I spent almost two hours to sort out what&#8217;s the best wifi network solution for me &#8211; I have two Linksys and one Airport Express, obviously too many options gave me too much troubles to do all tests. Finally I turn one (older), Linksys WRT54G2, running 802.11 B and G, and the other one (newer), <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/12/28/saving-my-home-network/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I spent almost two hours to sort out what&#8217;s the best wifi network solution for me &#8211; I have two Linksys and one Airport Express, obviously too many options gave me too much troubles to do all tests.</p>
<p>Finally I turn one (older), Linksys WRT54G2, running 802.11 B and G, and the other one (newer), E1000, running 802.11 N, it looks good so far.</p>
<p>I had to take the Kindle Fire all around the house to figure out the signal strength is good enough everywhere that I used to stay, it&#8217;s amazing that now we have so many mobile devices to deal with all sort of stuffs.</p>
<p>Also I found that I have way to many wireless devices at home &#8211; 3 laptops, 4 mobile phones, 2 eReaders (Kindle and Bambook), 2 game consoles, 2 Pads (iPad and Kindle Fire) and 1 television. I wish I didn&#8217;t miss anything. I&#8217;ve already raise the limit of DHCP client from 20 to 50 to avoid potential boost clients in case of party time or something similar, wish everybody comes in only with one mobile phone, hehe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Managing my cell phone numbers</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/09/03/managing-my-cell-phone-numbers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 05:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3g]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile phone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m setting up SMS forwarding and call forwarding now, why? Well, I used to get a Beijing number which I got 14 years ago so I don&#8217;t want to give up, after I came to Shanghai I purchased another Shanghai number so that people around me don&#8217;t have to do long distance call, then I <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/09/03/managing-my-cell-phone-numbers/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m setting up SMS forwarding and call forwarding now, why?</p>
<p>Well, I used to get a Beijing number which I got 14 years ago so I don&#8217;t want to give up, after I came to Shanghai I purchased another Shanghai number so that people around me don&#8217;t have to do long distance call, then I got another 3G number whenever I had problem in getting my home Internet connection.</p>
<p>My plan now &#8211; I&#8217;m going to forward SMS and phone calls to my Beijing number to my Shanghai number, and will keep 3G as a data plan (China Mobile&#8217;s 3G service sucks <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f641.png" alt="ðŸ™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> ). So after settling down the forwarding stuffs, I will go to find a dual card phone with WCDMA support, so I just need to carry one phone, and I can get all SMS and phone calls from both Shanghai and Beijing number, while keep online for all the time with my 3G.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
