<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mac &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/mac/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 02:03:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to make a bootable USB stick on Mac</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2015/02/21/how-to-make-a-bootable-usb-stick-on-mac/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2015/02/21/how-to-make-a-bootable-usb-stick-on-mac/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 02:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bootable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usb]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a good how-to: http://www.ubuntu.com/download/desktop/create-a-usb-stick-on-mac-osx]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a good how-to:</p>
<p>http://www.ubuntu.com/download/desktop/create-a-usb-stick-on-mac-osx</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2015/02/21/how-to-make-a-bootable-usb-stick-on-mac/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making progress</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/10/making-progress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 21:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[httpd filter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nginx]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After several days stuck in various problems, it seems I&#8217;m making progress now. First good news came from financial side &#8230; I found this site which is good for on-demand Mac &#8220;rental&#8221;, and obviously it saved me at least $200 (if I was to go with a refurbished Mac Mini). Now I just leave $30 <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/10/making-progress/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After several days stuck in various problems, it seems I&#8217;m making progress now.</p>
<p>First good news came from financial side &#8230; I found <a href="http://www.MacInCloud.com/">this site</a> which is good for on-demand Mac &#8220;rental&#8221;, and obviously it saved me at least $200 (if I was to go with a refurbished Mac Mini). Now I just leave $30 in my account, and occasionally log on to build my Apps. It was said that you have to log in at least every 60 days, or your money will be gone, this makes sense to me and does not bother me at all.<span id="more-1599"></span></p>
<p>Here comes things regarding development. AWS changed something, AWSiOSSDK became legacy and people should go with each individual framework for EC2, S3, and so on. Also, universal credential is no longer preferred and should create different virtual users for different access (this is really a great news!). I had made some changes to the aws-manager code, made EC2 works but S3 part still has some problem that I haven&#8217;t figured out why, but anyhow, this is a great progress, I just need to spend another hour or two to get this fixed.</p>
<p>ISAPI filter is making great progress, at least my simple filter works now, although it just does an unconditional redirect. Actually this should have been working at least a week ago, but &#8230; I stupidly change Visual Studio Express&#8217; setting, made a Debug build actually output everything to a Release directory, so all my efforts to make things work doesn&#8217;t make sense at all. I still could not recall why I made the change, but most likely at the time I started play with VS and I&#8217;m not that familiar with it. However, all the time spent on the debug was not a waste, as there are so many things I learnt <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f61b.png" alt="😛" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> &#8211; 32bit filter on 64bit IIS, attach to debug, different APIs, and so on.</p>
<p>I also complete conditional setting for Nginx filter, this was done in Apache module quite a while back but I was just too lazy to add the feature to Nginx. It was actually less then 20 lines of code, though.</p>
<p>Another thing is not so great but anyhow a good news, is that I decided to play with Scala and will be using Lift as the web framework. I will spend some time on this to get familiar with Java Web, then I can write my filter for Servlet Containers.</p>
<p>Maybe I can make all filters up and running by the end of this month? Let&#8217;s see :).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moved (back) to Windows</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/05/30/moved-back-to-windows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 01:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[osx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Give up MacBook Pro to someone else, and moved back to PC laptop. I was thinking of running Ubuntu on the new laptop so to fully utilize the 16G memory and 4-core i7 processor. However, after two days&#8217; painful trial, I finally gave up and moved back to Windows, and you can image &#8211; I <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/05/30/moved-back-to-windows/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Give up MacBook Pro to someone else, and moved back to PC laptop.</p>
<p>I was thinking of running Ubuntu on the new laptop so to fully utilize the 16G memory and 4-core i7 processor. However, after two days&#8217; painful trial, I finally gave up and moved back to Windows, and you can image &#8211; I moved back to Windows 7 instead of 8.</p>
<p>The problem with Ubuntu and Windows 8 are similar, they were not designed by following people&#8217;s common sense, or direct sense, whatever you want to name it. I, personally, believe the usability is OSX &gt; Windows 7 (Windows XP as well) &gt; Ubuntu (Windows Vista is almost the same) &gt; Windows 8.</p>
<p>Heard of Windows 8 is to be upgraded to have something like start button and program folders, etc. though it is still rumor so far. Shall we just name these changes as &#8220;graceful downgrade&#8221; in case they are really true? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f600.png" alt="😀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>BTW, I turned on Hyper-Thread on i7 processor so logically, I&#8217;m running a 8-core machine with 16G memory &#8211; this is my dreaming machine several years ago <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MS Office for Mac &#8230; sigh</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/03/16/ms-office-for-mac-sigh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 19:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[excel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[office]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What else can I say? It&#8217;s ridiclousely slow. I&#8217;m on Excel now, every single copy and paste took me close to a minute, without any reason. I tried to reboot the machine, re-compsoe the sheet, and lots of other tricks that I can imagine, but nothing works. Even Office in the VM on the same <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/03/16/ms-office-for-mac-sigh/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What else can I say? It&#8217;s ridiclousely slow.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m on Excel now, every single copy and paste took me close to a minute, without any reason. I tried to reboot the machine, re-compsoe the sheet, and lots of other tricks that I can imagine, but nothing works. Even Office in the VM on the same box works much faster.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MacPad</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/01/27/macpad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 07:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pad]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have to keep a record of ModBook, I got it from some RSS feed.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have to keep a record of <a href="http://eshop.macsales.com/Customized_Pages/modbook/modbook_customize.cfm?system=18b156bd-86d3-4679-8dd0-f2b942480fdc&#038;utm_campaign=mbordnw">ModBook</a>, I got it from some RSS feed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cisco VPN for Mac</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/01/09/cisco-vpn-for-mac/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 05:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vpn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I made Cisco VPN works on my MacBook, accidentally &#8230; I was talking to someone while randomly clicked on company&#8217;s web VPN site, and while discussing something I blindly clicked here and there and found that Advanced VPN does not work on my Mac, it soon took my attention and in several minutes, I figured <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/01/09/cisco-vpn-for-mac/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I made Cisco VPN works on my MacBook, accidentally &#8230;</p>
<p>I was talking to someone while randomly clicked on company&#8217;s web VPN site, and while discussing something I blindly clicked here and there and found that Advanced VPN does not work on my Mac, it soon took my attention and in several minutes, I figured it should be privilege issue (at least I guess). After manually download the installation shell script and run it with sudo, everything&#8217;s working now.</p>
<p>However, I used to start Cisco VPN on the Windows XP virtual machine running inside VirtualBox, it seems with the VPN moved to Mac itself (which is the host machine for VirtualBox), it became slower, significantly slower than before. I haven&#8217;t got time to dig out what was happening, but anyway, it is acceptable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Need to go to bookstore tomorrow</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/12/need-to-go-to-bookstore-tomorrow/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 13:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algoritm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I need to go to bookstore tomorrow for: Mac and iPhone development Android development Algorithms books in English I think I&#8217;m going to spend 200~300 RMB to get 3~4 books, wish me luck.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I need to go to bookstore tomorrow for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mac and iPhone development</li>
<li>Android development</li>
<li>Algorithms books in English</li>
</ul>
<p>I think I&#8217;m going to spend 200~300 RMB to get 3~4 books, wish me luck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New toy</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/07/new-toy-2/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/07/new-toy-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 10:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual box]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual machine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vmware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xcode]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Got an MacBook Pro 13&#8243;, but it&#8217;s an old model as the newest models are still pending on &#8220;regulator&#8217;s approval&#8221; in China, per Apple&#8217;s web site. I believe it&#8217;s the problem from the new Thunderbolt. Mine has 8G memory so I can run 3 VMs (under VirtualBox, each has 1G memory) plus all applications from <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/07/new-toy-2/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Got an MacBook Pro 13&#8243;, but it&#8217;s an old model as the newest models are still pending on &#8220;regulator&#8217;s approval&#8221; in China, per Apple&#8217;s web site. I believe it&#8217;s the problem from the new Thunderbolt.</p>
<p>Mine has 8G memory so I can run 3 VMs (under VirtualBox, each has 1G memory) plus all applications from Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Outlook), Safari, and several small utilities at the same time without any performance problem. For most time I only need to run 1 VM so it should be OK.</p>
<p>VirtualBox rolls, while Parallele Desktop and VMWare Fusion both suck. Alright I know I&#8217;m not familiar with either so VirtualBox gained my respect, but thinking of VirtualBox is free, this simply kills those two.</p>
<p>Installing Xcode was a nightmare &#8211; App Store in China didn&#8217;t work, at least for huge packages like Xcode (I installed some small stuffs without problem), finally I downloaded Xcode from Apple&#8217;s developer web site. There were not many to be installed as I can see, other than QQ and MPLayer. I&#8217;m trying to get Pidgin running now, but seems I have to run it under X11, and if this is the case I will move to Adium though I do want to have customized smileys. Maybe Adium got it already, need to check out.</p>
<p>Overall speaking, MBP is a nice laptop, it&#8217;s quiet, cool (against HOT MBP ppc I had 8 years ago). The only problem is that I have to remove my watch while working on it as chain of the watch will scratch the shell.</p>
<p>I ordered a keyboard screen and a bag for it, will get this week.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/07/new-toy-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finally, the PowerBook crashed</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/03/05/finally-the-powerbook-crashed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 07:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The PowerBook I got 4 years ago finally stopped working &#8211; it crashes every 5 minute. Is it time to get a new Mac machine? iMac? MacBook?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The PowerBook I got 4 years ago finally stopped working &#8211; it crashes every 5 minute.</p>
<p>Is it time to get a new Mac machine? iMac? MacBook?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moving to Mac?</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/12/04/moving-to-mac/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/12/04/moving-to-mac/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 19:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=806</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was said corp IT is now able to switch HP laptop with a MacBook, there is a guy in our group got his MacBook, and another guy&#8217;s request is being handled and will get in &#8220;couple of days&#8221;. I&#8217;m thinking now &#8211; maybe I should get my HP laptop replaced as well. I&#8217;m checking <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/12/04/moving-to-mac/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was said corp IT is now able to switch HP laptop with a MacBook, there is a guy in our group got his MacBook, and another guy&#8217;s request is being handled and will get in &#8220;couple of days&#8221;.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m thinking now &#8211; maybe I should get my HP laptop replaced as well. I&#8217;m checking software installed on my laptop now, so that I have some rough idea of what ability I&#8217;m going to lose by switching to Mac.</p>
<p>I believe I&#8217;m still going to have MS Office, and I will still have Firefox and Thunderbird, I will have Yahoo Messenger, and I think Adium can do all Pidgin does. I don&#8217;t think I need putty and WinSCP. I assume I can still get software for Blackberry and Nokia E90, but if they are not available it won&#8217;t be a big deal. I will have Perl, python, Java, subversion, etc. by default, which is good.</p>
<p>I may lose GNAT Ada, and have to find a better Common LISP environment. I need to find a good media player, while i think VLC should be good enough. Obviously I will lose all those Windows development environment, but if I can get Fusion I could run a Windows image (not sure about corp IT policy though). A new printer (all-in-on) is on the way and I believe it works with Mac (my current one does not work quite well).</p>
<p>Pretty much everything is fine :). I will submit the ticket after coming back from the Christmas vacation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/12/04/moving-to-mac/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
