<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>apache &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/apache/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 16:41:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Fixes applied after upgrading to 14.04 LTS</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2014/04/21/fixes-applied-after-upgrading-to-14-04-lts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 16:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ejabberd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[php]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roundcube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Several issues found after upgrade various version of Ubuntu to latest 14.04 LTS, luckily things are not that hard to fix. ejabberd does not work, turned to be ejabberd was trying to get rid of asn1, and there were some problem caused by that. Though ejabberd fixed the problem right away, it seems Ubuntu took <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2014/04/21/fixes-applied-after-upgrading-to-14-04-lts/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several issues found after upgrade various version of Ubuntu to latest 14.04 LTS, luckily things are not that hard to fix.</p>
<p>ejabberd does not work, turned to be ejabberd was trying to get rid of asn1, and there were some problem caused by that. Though ejabberd fixed the problem right away, it seems Ubuntu took the wrong version. What you should do is upgrade ejabberd from 2.1.11 to 2.1.12 (later version may work as well, but I didn&#8217;t try), <span id="more-1691"></span></p>
<p>and if you don&#8217;t know how to play with erl => beam compilation like me, you can just setup a Fedora VM and install ejabberd over there and copy eldap.beam from ejabberd package (NOTE: not the eldap.beam from ejabberd-eldap package) to the Ubuntu box.</p>
<p>RoundCube web mail does not work, it was cause by several issues. First, apach2 now only takes *.conf from site-enabled/ directory instead of former configuration of taking anything (I could have wrong impression on old release, but this is the cause). Second, dovecot&#8217;s configuration needs some tweak &#8211; you just need add a new section to 10-mail.conf with namespace inbox defined, which has inbox = yes inside. The last thing is, you need to enable mcrypt.ini in PHP&#8217;s apache configuration, you can do whatever you want, I just symlink mcrypy.ini from mods-available/ to apache/ and that&#8217;s it.</p>
<p>The new RoundCube interface looks good, I&#8217;m going to dig around to see if there is any other theme with different color, I always prefer light-blue/light-gray style.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ProxySourceAddress under Apache HTTPd</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2014/03/05/proxysourceaddress-under-apache-httpd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 20:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[httpd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ProxySourceAddress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squid]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just could not make it work although it seems pretty easy and straightforward. I have a machine with 4 IPs (216.x.x.203~206), and start Apache listening on 1203~1206 for each IP, then for each VirtualHost (such as 216.x.x.203:1203) I turn on ProxyRequests, and set ProxySourceAddress to that IP address, thus client connecting to 203 will <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2014/03/05/proxysourceaddress-under-apache-httpd/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just could not make it work although it seems pretty easy and straightforward.</p>
<p>I have a machine with 4 IPs (216.x.x.203~206), and start Apache listening on 1203~1206 for each IP, then for each VirtualHost (such as 216.x.x.203:1203) I turn on ProxyRequests, and set ProxySourceAddress to that IP address, thus client connecting to 203 will have their request go out through 203 as well.<span id="more-1674"></span></p>
<p>It just didn&#8217;t work, I&#8217;m having this kind of messages in error_log:<br />
<code><br />
(98)Address already in use: [client 192.168.0.11:48822] AH00938: CONNECT: failed to bind socket to local address<br />
</code></p>
<p>Tried various configuration changes but didn&#8217;t make any difference. Since I was in a hurry to get my job done, so I switch to squid &#8211; everything was up and running as expected in ~15 min. Thinking of I never play with squid before, I have to say, squid is pretty user (read: admin) friendly.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve downloaded code from for httpd-2.4.7, and will dig in to see if it was because of my potential stupid mistakes, let&#8217;s see how things work. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making progress</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/10/making-progress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 21:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[httpd filter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nginx]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After several days stuck in various problems, it seems I&#8217;m making progress now. First good news came from financial side &#8230; I found this site which is good for on-demand Mac &#8220;rental&#8221;, and obviously it saved me at least $200 (if I was to go with a refurbished Mac Mini). Now I just leave $30 <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/10/making-progress/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After several days stuck in various problems, it seems I&#8217;m making progress now.</p>
<p>First good news came from financial side &#8230; I found <a href="http://www.MacInCloud.com/">this site</a> which is good for on-demand Mac &#8220;rental&#8221;, and obviously it saved me at least $200 (if I was to go with a refurbished Mac Mini). Now I just leave $30 in my account, and occasionally log on to build my Apps. It was said that you have to log in at least every 60 days, or your money will be gone, this makes sense to me and does not bother me at all.<span id="more-1599"></span></p>
<p>Here comes things regarding development. AWS changed something, AWSiOSSDK became legacy and people should go with each individual framework for EC2, S3, and so on. Also, universal credential is no longer preferred and should create different virtual users for different access (this is really a great news!). I had made some changes to the aws-manager code, made EC2 works but S3 part still has some problem that I haven&#8217;t figured out why, but anyhow, this is a great progress, I just need to spend another hour or two to get this fixed.</p>
<p>ISAPI filter is making great progress, at least my simple filter works now, although it just does an unconditional redirect. Actually this should have been working at least a week ago, but &#8230; I stupidly change Visual Studio Express&#8217; setting, made a Debug build actually output everything to a Release directory, so all my efforts to make things work doesn&#8217;t make sense at all. I still could not recall why I made the change, but most likely at the time I started play with VS and I&#8217;m not that familiar with it. However, all the time spent on the debug was not a waste, as there are so many things I learnt <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f61b.png" alt="😛" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> &#8211; 32bit filter on 64bit IIS, attach to debug, different APIs, and so on.</p>
<p>I also complete conditional setting for Nginx filter, this was done in Apache module quite a while back but I was just too lazy to add the feature to Nginx. It was actually less then 20 lines of code, though.</p>
<p>Another thing is not so great but anyhow a good news, is that I decided to play with Scala and will be using Lift as the web framework. I will spend some time on this to get familiar with Java Web, then I can write my filter for Servlet Containers.</p>
<p>Maybe I can make all filters up and running by the end of this month? Let&#8217;s see :).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Updates</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/03/26/updates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 19:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cookie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[http filter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jetty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nginx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tomcat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, one and half month passed and I never post even a single word &#8230; yes I was busy but main reason is &#8230; I was lazy. Alright, some updates &#8211; I successfully migrate the bcookie module from Apache HTTPd to nginx, things were really tough at the very beginning whenever all you understand is <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/03/26/updates/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, one and half month passed and I never post even a single word &#8230; yes I was busy but main reason is &#8230; I was lazy.</p>
<p>Alright, some updates &#8211; I successfully migrate the bcookie module from Apache HTTPd to nginx, things were really tough at the very beginning whenever all you understand is Apache. However, at this stage I would like to say nginx is kind of neat and elegant, expanding it is not that hard though you have to build everything  in one shot (i.e. no dso allowed), I&#8217;d like to dig in why they have design like this as this is really uncommon in modern era.</p>
<p>And I&#8217;m moving to .Net now, again I have no idea so far, but I believe I need to write a filter in C# (YAY!), but before that I need get IIS up and running, and determine if there is any compatibility issues between different version of IIS (and .Net Framework).</p>
<p>Stay tuned, I will post whenever I make any progress and most likely that will be the time I move to Java container part &#8211; Jetty or Tomcat, not sure so far.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>apache_note() in PHP is sweet</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/01/25/apache_note-in-php-is-sweet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 21:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache_note]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[log]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[php]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was asked to find a solution to write customized Apache log entry (in Apache access log, not error log), other requirements include easy to use, which implicitly means &#8220;PHP friendly&#8221;, and flexible, which means &#8220;free format&#8221; and &#8220;may or may not have the value&#8221;. Seriously, the first thing jumped into my mind was an <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/01/25/apache_note-in-php-is-sweet/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was asked to find a solution to write customized Apache log entry (in Apache access log, not error log), other requirements include easy to use, which implicitly means &#8220;PHP friendly&#8221;, and flexible, which means &#8220;free format&#8221; and &#8220;may or may not have the value&#8221;.</p>
<p>Seriously, the first thing jumped into my mind was an Apache module (let&#8217;s hack mod_log!) or a PHP extension, but later on I found that &#8230; I don&#8217;t want to maintain another orphan project especially it will be orphan since nobody want to touch it after it&#8217;s up and running (I have one already, which does some cookie stuffs). So I move on to Google &#8230;</p>
<p>Then I found <a href="http://php.net/manual/en/function.apache-note.php">apache_note()</a>, plus <a href="http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.2/mod/mod_log_config.html">mod_log_config</a> (search for <code>%{<var>Foobar</var>}n</code>), all that I need to do is tell PHP guys to call this function, and tell ops guys to setup Apache log properly, we are all set.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s good to see apache_note can change the note as many times as you want, whenever the request is finished on server side, the final data will be written to log.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Playing with Hive</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/17/playing-with-hive/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/17/playing-with-hive/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 15:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hadoop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[log]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[map reduce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I got 700K lines of apache log files from a friend&#8217;s web server and imported them to the testing Hadoop instance running on my MacBoox, following the instructions listed here I successfully run some analysis. Note, the last section in the article talking about the Apache Weblog Data doesn&#8217;t seem to be correct &#8211; it <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/17/playing-with-hive/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I got 700K lines of apache log files from a friend&#8217;s web server and imported them to the testing Hadoop instance running on my MacBoox, following the instructions listed <a href="https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/GettingStarted">here</a> I successfully run some analysis.</p>
<p>Note, the last section in the article talking about the </i>Apache Weblog Data</i> doesn&#8217;t seem to be correct &#8211; it lacks of some space (&#8221; &#8220;) after ^ and it gave me quite some headache since I&#8217;m not familiar with Java regular expressions. Luckily <a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-662">Hive issue 662</a> mentioned in the article gave me the correct regex to get things done.</p>
<p>It seems I can only learn to play with Hive/Hadoop cos Hadoop running on MacBook is still a single node installation which is &#8230; <b>SLOW</b>, but so far I&#8217;m fine with it as I don&#8217;t have high volume of data to be processed. As a reference, getting top accessed IPs (which I used to figure out potential abusers) took 83 seconds. The HSQL is simple, something like &#8220;select host, count(*) cc from apachelog group by host order by cc desc limit 10;&#8221;.</p>
<p>Hadoop is a richmen&#8217;s game, seems it only improve the performance whenever you have lots of nodes as it can well distributed tasks.</p>
<p>BTW, <i>Hadoop: The Definitive Guide</i> is a good book <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> .</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/11/17/playing-with-hive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>hmmm &#8230; php and apache are still much more easier</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/24/hmmm-php-and-apache-are-still-much-more-easier/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 04:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[image]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[php]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have about 2,600 photos uploaded to one of my web sites, and I compose couple of quick PHP scripts to help me browse them. There is a img.php to resize the photo for different purpose (such as thumb view for listing page, medium size for view online, and full size for downloading), but whenever <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/24/hmmm-php-and-apache-are-still-much-more-easier/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have about 2,600 photos uploaded to one of my web sites, and I compose couple of quick PHP scripts to help me browse them. There is a img.php to resize the photo for different purpose (such as thumb view for listing page, medium size for view online, and full size for downloading), but whenever I try to download the photo, I found it&#8217;s tough as it always prompt to save as &#8220;img.php.jpeg&#8221;.</p>
<p>So, instead of doing any PHP stuff, I changed .htaccess under the folder, let apache do rewrite for me, in couple of minutes everything works like a chime.</p>
<p>These are really simple tasks, I guess it can be done with anything else (lighttpd, python, blar blar), but obviously I&#8217;m still familiar with PHP and Apache httpd, guess I should stick on that till something else can be this easy to me, just as years back I switched from qmail to postfix &#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
