<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>shanghai &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/shanghai/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 01:56:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Good food? Maybe &#8230;</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/07/08/good-food-maybe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 01:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[italian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shanghai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reading from some web site saying it&#8217;s one of the best Italian restaurant in this area, so I went there to try out those dishes recommended by other people, the result is &#8230; not that good, at least. The environment is just OK, not many people there but this could also prove that they are <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/07/08/good-food-maybe/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reading from some web site saying it&#8217;s one of the best Italian  restaurant in this area, so I went there to try out those dishes  recommended by other people, the result is &#8230; not that good, at least.</p>
<p>The environment is just OK, not many people there but this could also prove that they are not doing their business well. People there are just ok, not that professional, not that friendly, but they didn&#8217;t make any mistakes which made the dinner experience not that bad.</p>
<p>Food is not good at all, it could be the worst bread I ever had in a Italian restaurant. Salad is good, but too little to even feed one person. Soup is so so, I agree I don&#8217;t have good taste on soup so let&#8217;s ignore this part. What else? All dishes are kind of horrible, I don&#8217;t think it is even worse than what I can cook.</p>
<p>Never mind then, I will stop trying western food in the coming weeks or months. I guess some place may have something good during winter time, so I will try them again later on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hmmm &#8230; time to give some updates</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/07/07/hmmm-time-to-give-some-updates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 07:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shanghai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been away from this site for quite some time, there is only one reason for that &#8211; BUSY. I think I&#8217;d better put some time on this site as there may be still someone care about me and willing to read something here instead of somewhere else, so &#8230; Actually I have no idea where <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/07/07/hmmm-time-to-give-some-updates/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been away from this site for quite some time, there is only one reason for that &#8211; BUSY.</p>
<p>I think I&#8217;d better put some time on this site as there may be still someone care about me and willing to read something here instead of somewhere else, so &#8230;</p>
<p>Actually I have no idea where to start &#8211; I rent my apartment which is close to my office (20 min walk one way) so now I walk to office everything which seems making my life healthier. I used to get some breakfast on my way to office but I may try to find something new. I&#8217;m still skipping most of my lunches, and for dinner I had it with colleague (that will be a rich dinner) or have it alone (most time, it&#8217;s just a bowl of noodle).</p>
<p>Weather here in Shanghai is horrible, but seems I can still live with it, since I spend more of my time in office or at home, which means I have air conditioner for almost all the time. The only tough time is whenever I went out for smoking, but anyway that&#8217;s not healthy so let&#8217;s take it as punishment.</p>
<p>Business wise &#8230; things are just ok. It&#8217;s a big company now so it is not the pure start-up model that I was expecting, but things are still moving forward and I&#8217;m feeling busy now &#8211; after almost 2 years of &#8220;nothing to do&#8221;. I&#8217;m hiring, but I failed couple of times to get a product manager, so I think I&#8217;m going to focus on existing people, try to push some kids to see if they can grow fast enough. Engineer wise it&#8217;s mixed &#8211; I have problem in hiring expert on mail protocol (SMTP, POP, etc) as it is not that popular now but I have no problem finding people who want to do backend stuffs (distributed storage, etc), I didn&#8217;t pay too much attention on front-end engineer as it won&#8217;t be too bad, but I need to grab at least on in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>There are some business deals that I&#8217;m working on but I cannot share with public, but they are all moving smoothly. The BD manager who&#8217;s working with me is really really really smart, helped me striked pretty good deals and moving things forward even faster than I was expecting. He got a girl helping him now, and I wish the rest of the business negotiation will be as good as before.</p>
<p>Back to product, I have to prepare product plan due to lacking of product manager. Good thing is that I can learn to prepare those stuffs though I&#8217;ve been reading those B.S. for so many times, bad thing is that it&#8217;s time consuming.</p>
<p>Pretty much everything that I have at this moment, I will give out more things later on, once I have some.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
