<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ha &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/ha/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 18:03:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>ejabberd cluster</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/14/ejabberd-cluster/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/14/ejabberd-cluster/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 06:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cluster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ejabberd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xmpp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Time to play with HA ejabberd setup now. It was said number of daily active user will be less than 1M, and IM is just a feature of the mobile product, and believe that people will spend less then 2 hours on it everyday, also people will use the App mainly during traffic hours. So <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/14/ejabberd-cluster/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time to play with HA ejabberd setup now.</p>
<p>It was said number of daily active user will be less than 1M, and IM is just a feature of the mobile product, and believe that people will spend less then 2 hours on it everyday, also people will use the App mainly during traffic hours. So it&#8217;s 2M hours span to 7~9am and 6~8pm, 4 hours. I would like to assume it is evenly distributed, this makes the concurrent online user &#8230; 500K, Not a big number, and since it is just a non-key feature, so activities will be limited.</p>
<p>So I think I&#8217;d go with a full replicated ejabberd cluster, &#8220;full&#8221; means I&#8217;m going to replicate everything &#8211; password, roster, offline message. I will check the stats of the production environment to see how the resource utilization is going, and tune the allocation whenever necessary.<span id="more-1601"></span></p>
<p>Regarding the setup, pretty straightforward once I went through once (I did test on Ubuntu 12.04 LTS, but production eventually will be CentOS6):</p>
<p>1. setup node#1, change host (actually, it is domain for the XMPP service) in /etc/ejabberd/ejabberd.cfg, add mod_http_bind to modules (so to enable http-bind and http-poll), and change EJABBERD_NODE from &#8216;ejabberd&#8217; to &#8216;ejabberd@`hostname -f`&#8217; in /etc/default/ejabberd. You need to remove everything (except .erlang.cookie) under /var/lib/ejabberd then restart so to have the right mnesia DB.<br />
2. setup node#2, same as node#1, before restart ejabberd, copy .erlang.cookie from node#1<br />
3. run &#8220;ejabberdctl debug&#8221; as ejabberd, then:<br />
<code><br />
FirstNode = 'ejabberd@node#1', mnesia:stop(), mnesia:delete_schema([node()]), mnesia:start(), mnesia:change_config(extra_db_nodes, [FirstNode]), mnesia:change_table_copy_type(schema, node(), disc_copies).<br />
</code><br />
note that node#1 should be FQDN<br />
4. CTRL-C twice to quit (q(). used to work, but I don&#8217;t know what changed to erlang which makes it no longer works), then restart ejabberd. Run &#8220;ejabberdctl status&#8221; and &#8220;ejabberd mnesia info&#8221; to make sure the service is properly running on this host, and it is has node#1 included in DB node<br />
5. repeat 2~4 on all other nodes (I have 4 nodes in total)<br />
6. after all set, you can go to http://node/#1:5280/admin/ to make sure all nodes are in the cluster</p>
<p>Now &#8230; I believe it&#8217;s doable in ejabberdctl debug, but still could not figure out how. However, it&#8217;s easier to do it through web admin interface. I just change everything exactly the same as node#1 on all other nodes (RAM, disc, disc and RAM, etc). After that, do a reboot on all machines then use ejabberdctl status (or even with &#8211;nodes Node#N) to make sure everything can be up and running after a reboot.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m going to do LVS for XMPP port and nginx load balancer for 5280 (http-bind), will post result later.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/14/ejabberd-cluster/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
