<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>photo &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/photo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 05:24:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Frastrated</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/05/24/frastrated/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 05:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zune]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zune, or Windows Phone make me mad. There is no simple way to drag and drop the photos in the phone to a PC, and the phone cannot act like an USB drive, I mean there may be some way to make it but definitely not easy and direct. I searched online and found Library/Pictures/&#60;Device <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/05/24/frastrated/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Zune, or Windows Phone make me mad.</p>
<p>There is no simple way to drag and drop the photos in the phone to a PC, and the phone cannot act like an USB drive, I mean there may be some way to make it but definitely not easy and direct. I searched online and found Library/Pictures/&lt;Device Name&gt; is the place &#8230;</p>
<p>I also tried to enable Internet Sharing so that I can upload those photos to Windows Live site and then access from there, but I failed because Internet sharing cannot be enabled without mobile data connection enabled. What H***? I have wifi access, why bother to ask me turn on expensive mobile data network?</p>
<p>Actually I know it may not be all Windows Phone&#8217;s problem. I&#8217;m not in good mode in the past several days as frastrated by all sort of technical support kind of tasks, wish things can be better in the coming days.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why don&#8217;t I post photos here?</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/09/02/why-dont-i-post-photos-here/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 05:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/09/02/why-dont-i-post-photos-here/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, quick (and dirty :D) answer – I don’t have a camera with acceptable quality, and I don’t feel like to purchase a camera in near future. Longer (and more reasonable) answer – I don’t feel quite good in posting photos online, I’m no longer young, social networking is far away from me and I’ve <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2010/09/02/why-dont-i-post-photos-here/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, quick (and dirty :D) answer – I don’t have a camera with acceptable quality, and I don’t feel like to purchase a camera in near future.</p>
<p>Longer (and more reasonable) answer – I don’t feel quite good in posting photos online, I’m no longer young, social networking is far away from me and I’ve never been a person who likes show off.</p>
<p>Actually I posted some photos here a while back, but none of them includes a human being. I may post some more photos here but this will be still the rule.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
