<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>facebook &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/facebook/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 17:30:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>No, you cannot use my email address</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/01/04/no-you-cannot-use-my-email-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 17:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotmail]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Somebody (stupidly?) registered a Facebook account with my Hotmail E-Mail address and no matter whose fault it is, it became a live account without verifying the E-Mail address, and I started getting all sort of social event notifications. So I went to Facebook and do a password retrieval through the E-Mail address, I cannot believe <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/01/04/no-you-cannot-use-my-email-address/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Somebody (stupidly?) registered a Facebook account with my Hotmail E-Mail address and no matter whose fault it is, it became a live account without verifying the E-Mail address, and I started getting all sort of social event notifications.</p>
<p>So I went to Facebook and do a password retrieval through the E-Mail address, I cannot believe that even a unverified E-Mail address can be used as password recovery, so at last I successfully take over the account and shut it down.</p>
<p>I guess someone is crying now but if I didn&#8217;t do that I will be the one crying in the corner, I believe this is Facebook&#8217;s fault.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/29/facebook/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 14:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaixin001]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linkedin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I agree social network is sort of virus, you were brought into the game just because one of your friends is there, and then later on you will find all of your friends are there. This is what I found today &#8211; I registered my account a year back I guess (by the time I <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/29/facebook/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I agree social network is sort of virus, you were brought into the game just because one of your friends is there, and then later on you will find all of your friends are there.</p>
<p>This is what I found today &#8211; I registered my account a year back I guess (by the time I know kaixin001.com, and people mentioned it is just another facebook), and at that time there was not many friends playing there. When I checked again this morning, it seems 50% of my friends who regularly accesses internet has an account there.</p>
<p>Now the question is &#8211; how many of them use it daily or even weekly? This is so-called active user, but it seems to me pretty low, maybe 1/10. Well someone would say 10% is really a good number, but I believe social network should have higher active rate.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know how long I can play with this one, facebook is way too fun compare with linkedin, I get rid of kaixin001.com as I found it is just a social network, means other than play some games, I got nothing else, actually it was even not the good place to keep contact with friends, let&#8217;s see how facebook works,</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
