<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>predis &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/predis/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 20:31:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>PHPRedis</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/08/15/phpredis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 20:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[php]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phpredis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[predis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rpm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Need to play with PHP extension for redis for a while, and after reading several articles on the web, I decided to with PHPRedis instead of Predis because of performance. My goal is build up a webservice to proxy requests to backend redis servers, the web server is actually a proxy handling all routing related <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/08/15/phpredis/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Need to play with PHP extension for redis for a while, and after reading several articles on the web, I decided to with <a href="https://github.com/nicolasff/phpredis/">PHPRedis</a> instead of <a href="https://github.com/nrk/predis/">Predis</a> because of performance.</p>
<p>My goal is build up a webservice to proxy requests to backend redis servers, the web server is actually a proxy handling all routing related issues, so that clients don&#8217;t have to worry about hashing, sharding, etc. So I do prefer something pretty fast, though I don&#8217;t know how fast I need.</p>
<p>I dig out an article of <a href="http://supportex.net/2011/08/rpm-build-redis-library-package-php/">how to build up PHPRedis extension</a>, but need to get redis.ini from github to so that build won&#8217;t fail. However, if you are lazy you can just put &#8220;extension=redis.so&#8221; to redis.ini by yourself, anyway, all up to you. Determine name of tarball and directory in spec file is some sort of tricky, as it seems things changed every version. I was using nicolasff-phpredis-2.2.1-66-g89bdaf2.tar.gz and nicolasff-phpredis-89bdaf2, note that they are not identical though have some common parts.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve deployed the extension to one of my test box, and will do some tests later on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
