<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>replace-brick &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/replace-brick/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 20:25:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Planning GlusterFS</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/03/planning-glusterfs-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 20:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gluster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[replace-brick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Learnt from the mailing list that I should not export mounting point as a brick directly, instead I should create a sub-directory under the mounting point and take it as brick, this will make life much easier later on whenever you have to do migration or re-organization (like changing replica). Developers of GlusterFS are thinking <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/10/03/planning-glusterfs-2/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Learnt from the mailing list that I should not export mounting point as a brick directly, instead I should create a sub-directory under the mounting point and take it as brick, this will make life much easier later on whenever you have to do migration or re-organization (like changing replica).</p>
<p>Developers of GlusterFS are thinking of retiring replace-brick, from the mailing list I can see they have good point to do so (especially existing codes for replace-brick is too bad to be improved :P), however, as a (sort of) ops guy, I still prefer they can keep it since it makes ops&#8217; life much more easier, but obviously they don&#8217;t quite agree with all requests/challenges to keep it. Anyway, it seems life will not end, it will just become a little bit troublesome, and if this is the trade-off for stability and/or performance, I&#8217;m fine with it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
