<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>upgrade &#8211; Flying Bug</title>
	<atom:link href="https://xiehang.com/blog/tag/upgrade/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://xiehang.com/blog</link>
	<description>Debugging and Being Debugged</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 04:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Ubuntu 22.04</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2022/04/26/ubuntu-22-04/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 04:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fedora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parallels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[utm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordpress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.04 was just released, I managed to upgrade my WordPress site (running on VM and only publish static site), it was not as smooth as I thought, there were quite some small problems here and there, but eventually it worked after like 4 hours of troubleshooting, and so on. As a side note, I <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2022/04/26/ubuntu-22-04/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ubuntu 22.04 was <a href="https://ubuntu.com/blog/ubuntu-22-04-lts-released">just released</a>, I managed to upgrade my WordPress site (running on VM and only <a href="https://xiehang.com/blog/2022/03/04/move-to-static-site/">publish static site</a>), it was not as smooth as I thought, there were quite some small problems here and there, but eventually it worked after like 4 hours of troubleshooting, and so on.</p>
<p>As a side note, I no longer running Parallels since I found it tricked me to subscription which involves $79.99 per year, luckily I noticed the weird charge on my credit card so was able to cancel it the same day. I&#8217;m running my VM on <a href="https://mac.getutm.app/">UTM</a> now, I didn&#8217;t notice performance difference between UTM and Parallels, though Parallels does provide more convenient features like desktop integration, snapshot, etc.</p>
<p>I think I&#8217;ve been running Ubuntu since 10.04, but I&#8217;m seriously thinking of moving away from it now due to snap, there are more and more applications over Ubuntu dropped deb support and are solely on snap only, I don&#8217;t mind a distro changes its package management tool like yum to dnf, but I just don&#8217;t want to have 2 package management mechanism at the same time.</p>
<p>I may not run Fedora as I need LTS, I cannot choose Rocky as it (actually RHEL) lacks of aarch64 support. Most likely I&#8217;m going to play with Debian or Arch.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fixes applied after upgrading to 14.04 LTS</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2014/04/21/fixes-applied-after-upgrading-to-14-04-lts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 16:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ejabberd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[php]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roundcube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Several issues found after upgrade various version of Ubuntu to latest 14.04 LTS, luckily things are not that hard to fix. ejabberd does not work, turned to be ejabberd was trying to get rid of asn1, and there were some problem caused by that. Though ejabberd fixed the problem right away, it seems Ubuntu took <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2014/04/21/fixes-applied-after-upgrading-to-14-04-lts/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several issues found after upgrade various version of Ubuntu to latest 14.04 LTS, luckily things are not that hard to fix.</p>
<p>ejabberd does not work, turned to be ejabberd was trying to get rid of asn1, and there were some problem caused by that. Though ejabberd fixed the problem right away, it seems Ubuntu took the wrong version. What you should do is upgrade ejabberd from 2.1.11 to 2.1.12 (later version may work as well, but I didn&#8217;t try), <span id="more-1691"></span></p>
<p>and if you don&#8217;t know how to play with erl => beam compilation like me, you can just setup a Fedora VM and install ejabberd over there and copy eldap.beam from ejabberd package (NOTE: not the eldap.beam from ejabberd-eldap package) to the Ubuntu box.</p>
<p>RoundCube web mail does not work, it was cause by several issues. First, apach2 now only takes *.conf from site-enabled/ directory instead of former configuration of taking anything (I could have wrong impression on old release, but this is the cause). Second, dovecot&#8217;s configuration needs some tweak &#8211; you just need add a new section to 10-mail.conf with namespace inbox defined, which has inbox = yes inside. The last thing is, you need to enable mcrypt.ini in PHP&#8217;s apache configuration, you can do whatever you want, I just symlink mcrypy.ini from mods-available/ to apache/ and that&#8217;s it.</p>
<p>The new RoundCube interface looks good, I&#8217;m going to dig around to see if there is any other theme with different color, I always prefer light-blue/light-gray style.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Time to upgrade</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/01/18/time-to-upgrade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 19:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There was a e-waste recycling event close to my house and I successfully dumped these: an HP jet printer, an IBM ThinkPad (the very first Windows tablet, or in some other name), an HP desktop (Pentium 4!!!), some keyboards and mouses (actually this is some sort of illegal I guess? As they mentioned &#8220;anything with <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2013/01/18/time-to-upgrade/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There was a e-waste recycling event close to my house and I successfully dumped these: an HP jet printer, an IBM ThinkPad (the very first Windows tablet, or in some other name), an HP desktop (Pentium 4!!!), some keyboards and mouses (actually this is some sort of illegal I guess? As they mentioned &#8220;anything with a plug&#8221; but anyway &#8230;), a DVD player (I&#8217;m pretty sure it stopped working for quite some time). There are some other stuffs I hesitated to recycle because of this or that &#8211; a 1 mega pixel digital camera, 2 random brand cell phones (feature phone with color screen), two iPods, one camcorder, 2 LCD displays.</p>
<p>It seems the time to upgrade &#8211; the main desktop @ home is not performing quite well after upgrade to Windows 8, I&#8217;m thinking of replacing with a iMac, or a Windows 8 laptop &#8230; I don&#8217;t have enough machines to test cluster now and was thinking of virtual machine, but it seems better use some sort of mini PC so that I can test home automation as well (my dream &#8230; hard to come true without buying stuffs :D).</p>
<p>There may be more to come, let&#8217;s see.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MySQL was down for 2 days &#8230;</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/05/30/mysql-was-down-for-2-days/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/05/30/mysql-was-down-for-2-days/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 04:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[down]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysql]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[site]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s my fault not checking the status after upgrading the system, but obviously mysql upgrade on Ubuntu hit some problems and stopped in the middle leave the mysql totally inaccessible, which means, my site was down for two days. Well, I was really busy on job related stuffs, dealing contextual algorithms while playing with network, <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/05/30/mysql-was-down-for-2-days/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s my fault not checking the status after upgrading the system, but obviously mysql upgrade on Ubuntu hit some problems and stopped in the middle leave the mysql totally inaccessible, which means, my site was down for two days.</p>
<p>Well, I was really busy on job related stuffs, dealing contextual algorithms while playing with network, but this is not the real cause &#8211; I do need a monitoring tool to make sure my site is up and running, though it is not that critical.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/05/30/mysql-was-down-for-2-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moving to Ubuntu 12.04</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/04/27/moving-to-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/04/27/moving-to-ubuntu-12-04/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 16:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[12.04]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Migrating various hosts to 12.04, result is half-half &#8211; EC2 hosts got upgraded without any problem, I think I&#8217;m really lucky in this case as those EC2 hosts are serving live traffic, the VM and bridge host at home failed to reboot after upgrade, it seems the problem was because of boot disk/partition got rename/re-numbered, <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/04/27/moving-to-ubuntu-12-04/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Migrating various hosts to 12.04, result is half-half &#8211; EC2 hosts got upgraded without any problem, I think I&#8217;m really lucky in this case as those EC2 hosts are serving live traffic, the VM and bridge host at home failed to reboot after upgrade, it seems the problem was because of boot disk/partition got rename/re-numbered, but I&#8217;m not quite sure.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve re-installed VM, weird thing is that there was some free space on the harddisk so I can leave original partition untouched, after installation&#8217;s done, I found that I installed to /dev/sda6, while /dev/sda1 still has a bootable Ubuntu 12.04 which I just upgraded. I didn&#8217;t pay much attention on what I have done as I was thinking I&#8217;m gonna lose everything. I&#8217;m working on the bridge host now and will post details here if I find anything.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/04/27/moving-to-ubuntu-12-04/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upgrade to xcode 4.3.1</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/03/19/upgrade-to-xcode-4-3-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 20:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xcode]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I mentioned before, I accidently upgraded xcode, and obviously the upgrade (or something else caused by upgrade) broke my previous AWS app &#8211; at the beginning it does not build, and after tweak the project file, it refused to run. Instead of doing further more troubleshooting job, I just uninstall and reinstall the whole <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/03/19/upgrade-to-xcode-4-3-1/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned <a href="https://xiehang.com/blog/2012/03/17/dont-try-to-solve-every-single-problem/">before</a>, I accidently upgraded xcode, and obviously the upgrade (or something else caused by upgrade) broke my previous AWS app &#8211; at the beginning it does not build, and after tweak the project file, it refused to run. Instead of doing further more troubleshooting job, I just uninstall and reinstall the whole xcode tool chain, and obviously this is the simple and quick solution (other than Giga data of download).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Android 2.3.5 now</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/12/30/android-2-3-5-now/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 04:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[htc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[HTC G10 reminded me to upgrade Android and after ~20 minutes I&#8217;m running 2.3.5 now. Well, not that much improved from my limited experience except some cool UI effects, I will spend some more time to figure out if there is anything new or fun.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>HTC G10 reminded me to upgrade Android and after ~20 minutes I&#8217;m running 2.3.5 now.</p>
<p>Well, not that much improved from my limited experience except some cool UI effects, I will spend some more time to figure out if there is anything new or fun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Ubuntu is here</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/10/14/new-ubuntu-is-here/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/10/14/new-ubuntu-is-here/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubuntu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Log onto my server and it reminded me new release of Ubuntu is ready. Upgrading now, will post anything good/bad/special later on.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Log onto my server and it reminded me new release of Ubuntu is ready.</p>
<p>Upgrading now, will post anything good/bad/special later on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/10/14/new-ubuntu-is-here/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s being put online now</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/07/23/its-being-put-online-now/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 17:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=1115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are upgrading corporate E-Mail system now &#8211; it&#8217;s our first production E-Mail system :). It seems there are way too many things to be tested, people are working really hard on that but it still took quite some time. Now everything had been switched to the new system and we (alright, exclude myself) are <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2011/07/23/its-being-put-online-now/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are upgrading corporate E-Mail system now &#8211; it&#8217;s our first production E-Mail system :).</p>
<p>It seems there are way too many things to be tested, people are working really hard on that but it still took quite some time.</p>
<p>Now everything had been switched to the new system and we (alright, exclude myself) are busy verifying the system. It takes time, and I&#8217;m sleepy here &#8230;</p>
<p>Frankly speaking, I&#8217;ll pay more attention on public E-Mail system, but I know corporate E-Mail system will kill us sooner or later based on my previous experience.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upgrade problem all the places</title>
		<link>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/12/upgrade-problem-all-the-places/</link>
					<comments>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/12/upgrade-problem-all-the-places/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 03:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Triviality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fedora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smiley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upgrade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordpress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://xiehang.com/blog/?p=459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While I was trying to upgrade a friend&#8217;s Fedora machine from 10 to 11, I found that the yum got some problems with mirrorlist file, which had been addressed with Fedora/yum guys, but so there there is no fix, just a workaround. Then yesterday WordPress prompted there is a new version can be upgraded to, <a href='https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/12/upgrade-problem-all-the-places/' class='excerpt-more'>[...]</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I was trying to upgrade a friend&#8217;s Fedora machine from 10 to 11, I found that the yum got some problems with mirrorlist file, which had been addressed with Fedora/yum guys, but so there there is no fix, just a workaround.</p>
<p>Then yesterday WordPress prompted there is a new version can be upgraded to, so I did &#8230; everything went smoothly, automatic upgrade, so fancy, but after upgrade &#8211; hold on, all my posts became PHP error message.</p>
<p>Obviously the new 2.8 does not support old smiley well, or at least it changed requirement of the smileys&#8217; pattern. I haven&#8217;t found the root cause yet so I don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s the workaround so far, so I just simply disabled smiley and seems it works fine to me, so far.</p>
<p>I will post here later if I found anything.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://xiehang.com/blog/2009/06/12/upgrade-problem-all-the-places/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
